Move!
走起来
- I was born for battle.
我天生就是打仗的料
Built for it.
具备打仗应有的素质
Sometimes in battle, a perfectly crafted plan gets compromised.
有时在战斗中 精心设计的计划会遭破坏
A true general comes up with a better one right there on the spot,
一位真正的将军 当场就能想出一个更好的计划
working without a net
冒着风险采取行动
and sticking the landing to thunderous applause.
然后在雷鸣般的掌声中 圆满地完成任务
- Hurry up, you dogs!
快点 狗崽子们
Let's go! Let's go!
快走
- Where are they?
他们在哪儿
- They were coming straight at us and then veered away on a sidetrack.
他们当时直冲我们过来 然后转到了一条侧轨上
This line bends Southwest.
这条轨道拐向西南方
At that speed, they could be 20 kilometers away by now.
以那个速度 他们此刻可能已在20公里之外
- Or coming about to nip at our heels.
或者已调头 跟在我们后面
- I'm sorry, sir. There was no warning.
对不起 先生 这事事先没一点征兆
- No, they saw to that, didn't they? No satellite coverage.
当然 他们确保了这一点 不是吗  趁没有卫星信号
A moonless night. An ambush from the shadows!
在无月之夜 从阴影中伏击我们
- As cowardly as the day they left, sir.
就跟他们离开的那天一样懦弱
- No, they didn't drive by for nothing.
不 他们从我们身边经过肯定有阴谋
Forward lamps to full.
把前灯开到最大
Brake!
刹车
There's a moment in a fight when that first blow lands
在战斗中 有那么一刻 你被对方的第一击击中后
and everything stops.
一切仿佛都静止了
And in that flash of clarity, you know who you are.
在那一瞬间 你心开目明 认清了自己是谁
I'll push as hard as it takes to get my engine back.
我会竭尽全力夺回我的机车
Snowpiercer, 1,023 cars long.
1023节车厢长的雪国列车
Full thrust. Push through it.
加大马力 冲过去
- Sir, if that axel-- - Full power, Engineer. Now!
-可是 先生 如果车轴… -全速前进 工程师 快
- Well done, sir. Round one to you.
干得漂亮 先生 第一局您赢了
- No, no, that trap wasn't meant to stop us.
不 他们放那个陷阱 不是为了让我们停下
It was meant to slow us down.
而是为了让我们减速
We can't have any setbacks today, Kevin.
凯文 我们今天不能受任何挫折
Ruth's people will be energized. Find them.
鲁丝的人会受到激励的 去把他们找出来
- I know just where to start.
我正好知道该从何着手
- Take the gloves off.
手段狠点
Make an example.
杀鸡儆猴
- I thought you'd never ask.
就等着您这么吩咐呢
- And Kevin? - Yes, sir.
-凯文 还有件事 -您说 先生
- Send Zarah to me.
让扎拉到这里来
What's our speed?
我们现在的速度是多少
- 14 kilometers an hour.
每小时14公里
- All right, Mr. Layton, you got us at a crawl.
好啊 雷顿先生 你已迫使我们慢如爬行
What's the play?
你有什么花招呢
Layton knows better than to connect end to end.
雷顿知道车尾对接是行不通的
My Jackboots would just sweep in and crush him.
我手下的军靴可以直接冲进去击败他
So he's going to peck at us from the side.
所以 他会从侧面袭击我们
- He needs parallel track.
他需要一条并行的轨道
- And this rail yard is an entire maze of it.
而这片铁路站场就像个迷宫 布满了并行轨道
He broke free of the snare but slowed down.
他们摆脱了陷阱 但速度慢了下来
- We can get right up alongside him in these sidings.
我们可以在这些侧线上 赶上他们 与其并行
They'll be in position in 2 kilometers.
他们距离那里还有2公里
- Bring us around, Ben.
本 调头
- Copy that. - How long we got?
-收到 -有多少时间
- Three, four minutes.
三四分钟
- All right, stay sharp. Let's get this done.
好 机警点 咱们把这事给办了
I'll make sure Josie's ready.
我去确保乔西已做好准备
- Bess.
贝丝
♪ Bess Till
贝丝提尔
♪ Bess! - Audrey, shut it.
-贝丝  -奥德丽 闭嘴
- What's happening? Is it him?
出什么事了 是他吗
- You'll know it's him when his head is on a pike.
他的脑袋被插在长矛上时 你就会知道是他了
- You ready for this?
你准备好了吗
- Ben takes us close. I jump over, breach the Big Alice engine,
本开到他们边上后 我就跳过去 进大爱丽丝的机车
and you reconnect.
然后你们重新连接两车
- We only get one shot at it.
我们只有一次机会
- Well, then, better not miss it.
那就最好别错失这个机会
- Zarah,
扎拉
just in time.
你来得正是时候
Thought you should be here for this.
我觉得你该看看这个
- As a hostage or a spectator?
以人质的身份还是旁观者的身份
- As my confidante, nothing less.
以我的红颜知己的身份
Come.
来
Come on.
来啊
Have a look.
看一下
See,
看到没
that's your old life creeping up our flank.
从我们侧翼悄悄追上来的 是你的旧相好
- Are they attacking?
他们要攻击我们吗
- Maybe they're here to surrender.
也许他们是来投降的
You see any white flags?
你看到白旗了吗
- No. - No.
-没有 -没有
No, and if I had to guess,
如果非得让我猜的话
I'd say they're trying to cut the head off the snake.
我觉得他们是冲着龙首而来的
But I have a surprise for them.
但我有个惊喜要送给他们
- Heave.
传下去
Heave.
快点传
- Well, whatever these tin cans are for can't be good.
不管这些锡罐是做什么用的 肯定不是什么好事
- Pike, man, what's the plan?
派克 你有什么计划
- Keep your eyes on your work.
专心干活
- Heave. - And quit standing around! Let's go.
-继续传 -嘿 别呆站着
- Come on. What are you doing?
快点 你在干什么呢
- All right, time to move. I'll distract them. You guys get to Ruth.
好 该行动了 我去引开他们 你们去找鲁丝
- No. Whoa, whoa. That's not how it works, man.
不行 不能这么做
You're in charge now. You don't get caught.
你现在是负责人了 你不能被抓
Catch.
接着
- We're in position.
我们已经就位
- Josie, it's time.
乔西 是时候了
Be careful out there.
在外面当心点
- I'll breach the bastard, don't worry.
我会毁掉那引擎的 别担心
Now! Harpoon!
就是现在 鱼叉炮
- Deploy.
准备发射
- Opening cold-lock.
正在打开冷封门
Wilford has a cannon or something. Pull back!
威尔福德有一个 像大炮的玩意儿 往后撤
- Switch track. Josie, hold on.
马上更换轨道 乔西 抓紧了
- We're derailing! - Try to stabilize.
-我们要脱轨了 -设法稳住
- Well done.
干得漂亮
Never fails to amaze me.
你总能令我惊讶
You take so much in and give so little back.
受到这么大刺激 却没什么反应
I just hobbled your man, Zarah, and you didn't even flinch.
我刚射残了你男人的列车 扎拉 可你连眼睛都没眨一下
At this rate, the war will be over by daybreak.
照这个速度下去 黎明前这场战争就会结束
- Come on. The car is damaged. We gotta go. Let's go.
拜托 嘿 这节车厢受损 我们得离开这里
- We have to cut it loose. It's gonna derail us.
得把车厢断开 否则我们会脱轨的
- Cut here? That's four cars.
从这里断开 那可是四节车厢啊
- It's the closest J-link. It's the only option.
这是最近的连接处 这是唯一的选择
- Asha's back there. - We don't have time.
-阿莎在那后面 -我们没时间了
- Go.
快走
- You okay?
你没事吧
Thank you.
谢谢
- She waited eight years outside. Can't very well kill her on day two.
她在外头坚持了八年 不能上我们列车第二天就被害死呀
- Safety's off.
安全栓已解除
- Disconnecting now
开始断开连接
And we're clear.
断开了
- Here.
这边走
You'll be safer up here.
你在这里会更安全
Hey...
嘿
You gonna be okay?
你不会有事吧
- Turn out the lights.
把灯关了
- Sure.
没问题
Hold fast, okay?
待着别动 好吗
- We have a problem.
我们有麻烦了
Wilford's gone.
威尔福德不见了
His train went dark. He could be anywhere now.
他关闭了列车的信号和灯光 不知道他们在哪里
- Switch off comms and transmitters tip to tail. Not a peep.
关闭全车上下的通讯和信号传输 停止一切声响
Zarah, what are you doing still on your feet?
扎拉 你怎么还站着呀
You must be exhausted. Come.
你一定累坏了 过来
- So what are you planning?
那你有什么打算
Bit of a lull. It'll do us good.
稍微歇一下对我们有好处
Catch our breath.
喘口气
I've invested a lot in you. And the child.
我在你和这孩子身上投入了很多
I just want to keep you near me,
我只是想让你待在我身边
for your protection.
为了保护你
- And because they won't attack the engine if I'm in it.
而且如果我在机车里 他们就不会攻击这里
- Right.
没错
- How do you lose a 10-mile train?
十几公里长的列车 你怎么能跟丢了呢
- We were the ones that led him into this maze.
是我们把他带到这片迷宫里的
- He could be running. These six routes head out of the valley.
他可能想逃出去 这六条线路通向谷外
If he gets to linear track, we'll lose our advantage.
如果他进入了直线轨道 我们就失去了优势
- Yeah, or he's around the next corner, laying in wait.
嗯 他也可能 正在下一个拐角等着我们
- He's gonna pick us off piece by piece.
他会把我们的列车一节节地废掉
I looked into the muzzle of that thing.
当时那玩意的炮口正对着我
- We need to get eyes on him. Can we get to higher ground?
我们必须找到他 我们能去高一点的地方吗
- Here, track follows the ridgeline. Should give us a view of the whole basin.
这里 这条轨道沿着山脊线 应该能让我们看到整个盆地
- Okay, let's do it. Lights out. If he's gonna go dark, so do we.
好 就这么办 把灯熄了 如果他打算隐身 我们也一样
- Up and at 'em, lovebirds.
小情侣 起来干活了
- Kevin! Get out. How dare you?
凯文 出去 你太过分了
- Commandeering the Nightcar.
夜车被我征用了
- Ugh, Kevin.
凯文
- On whose authority?
谁批准的
- Call it a wartime measure.
你可以称之为“战时举措”
Oh, you didn't hear? Layton's back.
你们没听说吗 雷顿回来了
Up.
起来
There's work to do.
还有活儿要干呢
- Why don't you, um, go put some coffee on?
要不你去煮点咖啡吧
- Who--who's there?
谁在那里
- Here to see the prisoner. I'm her lawyer.
我是来见囚犯的 我是她的律师
- I don't think that's a thing anymore.
我觉得现在已经没有律师这回事了
- Lose your helmet, Jackboot?
军靴 你把头盔摘掉了
- Hey, come on, man.
嘿 别这样 哥们
Hey.
嘿
- Do you know me?
你认识我吗
- You're--you're a Tailie. Forgive me, I-I don't know your name.
你是个末等人 抱歉 我不知道你叫什么
- I know you.
我认识你
Whiggins.
你姓惠金斯
- Yes.
对
- Well, there's two things you should know about Tailies.
关于末等人 有两件事你该知道
We have long memories and we win wars.
我们的记性很好 而且打仗我们总赢
- Oh, yeah?
是吗
We won the last one. And we'll win this one.
上一场战争是我们赢了 这一场也一样
And do you wanna be the guy who stands in the way?
你想当个碍我们事的人吗
Hmm, Whiggins?
惠金斯
- You have ten minutes, Counselor.
律师先生 给你十分钟的时间
Let me just get the door for you.
我替你开门
- Pike?
派克
- You're looking good, girl, with those arms dangling down.
姑娘 你的气色不错啊 没有缺胳膊少腿
- You shouldn't be here. It's too dangerous.
你不该来这里 太危险了
- I'm gonna get you out of here. - Wait, wait, wait. Tell me what happened.
-我得把你弄出去 -等等 告诉我发生了什么
- Wilford drove Layton off with cannon fire. Now we're rolling around in the dark.
威尔福德用大炮把雷顿赶走了 此刻我们正在黑暗中瞎转
- Well, if Wilford is hiding, then we need to signal Layton.
如果威尔福德在躲着雷顿 那我们就得给雷顿发信号
- I'm gonna get you out of here first.
我得先把你救出去
- You can't. You'd have to kill Whiggins, and then you'd have to find Clifford
不行的 要救我 你得先杀了惠金斯 然后找到克利福德
and kill him too, 'cause he's got the keys.
把他也杀了 因为钥匙在他手里
- Go on.
还有谁 继续说
- Pike, Mr. Pike,
派克先生
you're a dear man and a brave one,
你是个好人 一个勇敢的好人
but this war is bigger than us.
但这场战争比你我都重要
- How do I signal Layton?
我要怎么给雷顿发信号呢
- I've got an idea,
我有个主意
but you'll have to get uptrain to hospitality.
但你得去列车前列的待客部
Asha. Hey, you good in there?
阿莎 你还好吗 在这里还行吗
I'm sorry, I dropped you right in the thick of it. Here.
对不起 我们让你卷进了 最激烈的对抗中 来
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
嘿
- What's going on?
发生什么事了
Did Mr. Wilford cripple the train?
威尔福德先生把这列车弄坏了
- No, look, it's just some cat and mouse, all right?
没有 听着 这只是猫鼠之争 好吗 没事的
It's fine.
你们是猫
- And you're supposed to be the cat? Eight of you against the great Mr. Wilford.
你们八个人 要对付伟大的威尔福德先生
- The great Mr. Wilford is not who you think he is.
“伟大的威尔福德先生” 跟你想象中的不一样
- Isn't he the one that saved all of you?
不是他救了你们大家吗
- We saved our own damn selves.
是我们自己救了自己
He built all of this just so he could be king.
他打造这列列车 只是为了自己能称王
- So now it's your turn? - No. This is personal for us, okay?
-那现在轮到你称王了 -不 这是我们的私人恩怨 好吗
I have a partner that I boarded with. I have a child on the way.
登上列车时 我有一个伴侣 她现在怀着身孕
- Oh, if you're doing this for a child, you will do things that you will regret.
如果你这么做是为了一个孩子 你会做出让自己后悔的事的
- I just came in to warn you.
我只是过来警告你
We are not giving up.
我们不会放弃的
This is gonna get worse before it gets better, okay?
局势好转之前 会变得更加恶劣 明白吗
- Okay. - Hold on.
-明白 -坚持住
- ♪ You are my sunshine
你是我的阳光
♪ My only sunshine
我唯一的阳光
♪ You make me happy
当天空灰暗时
♪ When skies are gray
会带给我欢乐
♪ You'll never know, dear
你永远都不知
♪ How much I love you
我有多么爱你
♪ Please don't take My sunshine away
请别将我的阳光带走
- You know, when you sing,
要知道 你唱歌的时候
I can almost convince myself you're not a horrible person.
我几乎都能说服自己说 你的为人并不坏
- Thank you.
谢谢
- And then I remember you only sing covers, so the words aren't actually yours.
然后我会想起来你只翻唱别人的歌 所以歌词其实不代表你的心声
- Lyrics are just dressing.
歌词只是点缀而已
I sing for him.
我只为他歌唱
- Oh, God.
老天
- You scoff,
你显得很不屑
but at the end of the day, that's all there is.
但归根结底 那就是全部
A person you sing for.
你为之歌唱的那个人
Who's that to you, Bess?
贝丝 你的那个人是谁
How do you get all the way to the end of the world and have no one?
你一路坚持到了世界末日 居然会没有一个那样的人
- I have people.
我有
- Who?
谁
- Layton, Zarah, Roche.
雷顿、扎拉、罗齐
- Roche?
罗齐
- Yeah, Roche.
没错 罗齐
He was like a mentor to me and--and a friend.
他就像我的导师兼益友
Even though I fought him, he-- he had my back.
尽管我跟他对着干 他还是罩着我
No, I don't-- I don't sing for him.
不 我不会为他歌唱
But not a day goes
但是每一天
by when I don't think about getting him out of those Drawers.
我都在想着把他从抽屉房弄出来
- I'm sorry.
我很遗憾
I hope he survived.
希望他能活下来
- Yeah.
是呀
- We're at the ridge. Eyes up.
我们在山脊上了 注意观察
If he is in the valley, this is the best vantage point.
如果他在山谷里 这是能找到他的最佳位置
- Anything? - Till?
-有发现吗  -提尔
Negative. There's nothing.
没有 什么都没发现
- But they can't just vanish.
但他们不可能就这样消失不见啊
- Time to put on a show.
好戏登场
To the south, far end of the valley. Are you guys seeing this?
看南面 在山谷的尽头 你们看到了吗
- Oh, my God. Wait, wait, wait.
我的天啊 等等
Is that-
那是…
They're still with us.
我们的支持者还在
- We see you, Joseph.
看到你了 约瑟夫
- He's making a break for it. East over the ridge to the trunk line.
他正试图逃跑 在山脊东侧 往干线方向去
He wants to sneak out of the rail yard because it's where we have tactical advantage.
他想偷偷溜出铁路站场 我们在这里有战术优势
- If he gets out of the valley, he's looking at days of linear track.
他要是跑出去了 接下去好几天就都是直线轨道
- Can we beat him to it?
我们能赶到他前面去吗
- Alex? - No.
-艾莉  -不行
I don't know, maybe. It's all assumptions.
我不知道 也许行吧 我没把握
- What are we waiting for? Pedal down.
那我们还等什么 加速啊
- Let's cut 'em off at the pass.
我们在山口截住他
- Full throttle, Engineer.
工程师 加足马力
- Sir, with respect, we're draining really fast.
先生 恕我直言 我们的油耗非常快
A few ticks slower would be more efficient.
稍微开慢点 燃油效率会更高
- They've seen us. They're coming!
他们已经看到我们了 他们要来了
Tap every last reserve and get us over that bloody ridge!
用上所有的储备燃油 越过这该死的山脊
- Come on! What are you doing?
拜托 你这是干什么
- So you have a choice, Strong Boy.
强壮男孩 给你挑
I can take two fingers next time or I can take your thumb.
接下来要我砸碎两根手指呢 还是砸碎你的拇指
Or you could be smart
你也可以聪明一点
like when you bravely volunteered to step up to my table here.
就像你自告奋勇 到我桌子这里来时一样
Wilford just needs you to start talking and name your collaborators.
威尔福德只是要你提供信息 报出你同党的姓名
No.
不干
- No? - Come on. Leave him alone!
-不干  -拜托 别再折磨他了
- Hold him. - Ah, no! No!
-抓住他 -不要
Stop!
够了
- I didn't sign up for this.
我没答应过要趟这浑水
Just wanted to serve some drinks and play some tunes.
我只是想经营夜总会 提供酒水和歌曲
- Would you relax? War is not pretty.
你能放松点吗 战争都是丑陋的
But Wilford will reward us.
但威尔福德会奖励我们的
- If he wins.
前提是他能赢
- Of course he'll win.
他当然会赢
If he doesn't?
万一他输了呢
- And Layton rolls in here, finds this? Finds us?
到时候雷顿进来发现这件事 知道我们也在场 怎么办
Wilford's little wedding puppets.
威尔福德的傀儡夫妻
- We're not the torturers, all right? We're just providing a venue.
行刑的人又不是我们 我们只是提供了场地而已
- I'm sure the mutilated guy will be quick to sort that out.
我觉得被肢解的这个家伙 可不会这么认为
Look, if you're not gonna talk,
听着 如果你不打算开口
I guess you don't need that tongue anymore.
那你就不再需要这舌头了
Hold him, please.
请抓好他
Hold him, hold him.
抓好他
Open up.
张嘴
- Look, even if we catch up with him, we still have the harpoon issue,
听着 即便我们追上了他 我们还是要应付他的鱼叉炮
and we can't connect end to end.
我们也没法进行车尾对接
We'll never overpower his Jackboots.
因为我们绝对打不过他的军靴
- No.
没错
So we need a plan to get into his engine. We need a distraction.
所以我们得想办法进入机车 我们需要引开他的注意力
- Audrey.
奥德丽
- What's this?
这是要干什么
- Hands behind your back.
手放在背后
- Ooh, handcuffs. I knew you had a kink.
手铐 我就知道你有性怪癖
- Move.
快走
- Good luck.
祝好运
- It's moody in here.
这里的气氛很压抑嘛
- Sit.
坐下
- How much further?
还有多远
- We're almost at the ridge, but we're basically running on fumes.
快到山脊了 但我们的燃油即将耗尽
- Keep pushing. She'll make it. Then we're home free.
继续开 它能行的 然后就胜券在握了
- Nice and easy, Ben.
悠着点 本
- Joseph.
约瑟夫
- Big Alice, this is Snowpiercer. Come in.
大爱丽丝 这里是雪国列车 请回话
Snowpiercer to Big Alice, come in.
雪国列车呼叫大爱丽丝 请回话
- Sir, should--should I answer?
先生 我该回答吗
- No, no.
不要
- Come in, Big Alice.
大爱丽丝 请回答
- This is Big Alice. To whom am I speaking?
这里是大爱丽丝 我在跟谁通话呢
- I'm the guy standing between you and open track, Wilford.
威尔福德 我是那个 挡在你和开放轨道之间的人
- I see that. So it's a game of chicken, is it?
我看到了 这么说 现在就看谁的胆子更大了 是吗
- At the rate you're going, I don't think you'll make it this far.
按你们行进的速度 我觉得你开不到那么远
- Oh, Big Alice has more fight than you know.
大爱丽丝的韧劲比你想象的强
You called this meeting, Layton.
雷顿 这次会面是你发起的
So go on, or are we just gonna stand here pissing off our prows?
所以 有话快说 没必要在这里做无聊的争执
- When we left, we made a deal.
我们离开时 你我有个约定
I keep Audrey safe--
我确保奥德丽安全…
- I remember, and I don't murder everyone.
我记得 我就不把大家杀了
Yes, I remember the deal.
是的 我记得我们的约定
It was made under duress, I'll remind you.
我要提醒你一句 那是在胁迫下作出的约定
But I stuck to it.
但我还是遵守了
- Where's Zarah?
扎拉呢
- She's right here.
她就在这里
Positively glowing.
满面红光
- I'm here, Andre. I'm okay.
我在这里 安德烈 我没事
- And Audrey?
奥德丽呢
I want to hear her.
我想听到她的声音
I need to know she's all right.
我得知道她没事
- Surrender the train and you can tell her yourself.
交出列车控制权 你就可以亲自跟她说话了
- Surrender?
交出控制权
- We'll give you a car in First, food, drink.
我们会给你们一节头等车厢 提供美食酒水
You two can live out your years together.
你们俩可以相守到老
- So I--I give you absolutely everything,
也就是说 我把一切都给你
and you give me a little piece back in return?
而你只会给我一点小小的恩赐
That's quite some offer, Layton.
这个提议太可笑了吧 雷顿
- The offer is, we end this without violence,
我的提议是 用非暴力的形式了结这件事
or you could roll back down into that rail yard and we'll pick you apart.
否则就回到那个铁路站场 我们会把你拆成碎片
- That's it, sir. We're tapped.
完了 先生 燃油耗尽了
- No deal.
我拒绝
I...I want to hear her voice.
我想听听她的声音
- Joseph.
约瑟夫
- All right, Ben, I'm at the cold-Lock.
好了 本 我到冷封门了
Soon, soon.
快了
- Auto-engaging hot reverse.
设置自动驾驶 急速后退
We should switch helms and get Big Alice pushing again.
我们应该调换一下车尾车头 让大爱丽丝在后面推
- Full stop, Engineer.
停车 工程师
Let her power down.
关闭电源
- What? - Joseph.
-什么  -约瑟夫
- That can't be good,
这不可能是好事
can it?
会是好事吗
- No.
不会
- Snowpiercer,
雪国列车
we are dead on the tracks.
我们没动力 启动不了了
If you don't reconnect, everyone will freeze to death.
如果你们不跟我们连接 列车上所有的人都会冻死
- You're desperate.
你这是不顾一切了
- And you have no choice.
而你则没得选择
- Prepare to connect. Javi, abre una cerveza, amigo.
准备连接 哈维…
- Commander, move your boarding party to the connection point.
指挥官 把你的突击小组 派到连接点去
- Generation deficit.
发电不足容量
Train-wide temperature is dropping right now.
整个列车的温度正在下降
- Better get your woolies on.
最好把你的毛衣穿上
- All right, boys, you ready?
来吧 小伙子们 准备好了吗
- Move out. Remember where to aim.
出去 瞄准中心点 记住射击目标
- They're preparing to dock.
他们在准备连接了
- They've got no choice.
他们别无选择
Let's go, let's go. Move, move, move.
又要开始了 快走 快
- Cap okay?
驾驶舱没问题
- Hey, watch your back. Move it, move it!
嘿 留神点 进去
- This is crazy, Ben.
这太疯狂了 本
- Yeah, pirate's life.
是呀 强盗生涯就是如此
- Shit.
见鬼
- You're all right.
没事的
Just reverse her in as fast as you dare.
用你敢开的最快速度倒车
- Shit.
见鬼
- And don't reconnect until we're in position.
我们就位之前不要与对方连接
- Hey, remember, people, we're gonna clear it first.
好了 各位 记住 我们要先把对方清除干净
- Weapons ready? Move!
武器准备好 上
- Christ.
老天
Josephine.
乔瑟芬
She's back.
她回来了
The bloody balls.
真够有种的
Did you climb aboard, you little hobo?
你是爬上来的吗 小流浪汉
Uh-uh, baby on board.
这里有孕妇哦
No, you won't.
不 你不会的
She won't.
她不会的
Damn. Good one.
见鬼 真够狠的
- Tell your men to stand down or I will throw you off this train.
叫你的人退下 否则我就把你扔出列车去
- This is Head Engineer Wilford.
我是首席工程师威尔福德
Boarding party, stand down.
突击小组 退下
We will not be taking...
我们不打算…
Snowpiercer by force.
用武力拿下雪国列车
Stand down. Weapons down.
退下 放下武器
- Oh, my God.
我的天啊
- Happy now?
这下开心了
- Say it!
快说
- Andre Layton has the train.
安德烈雷顿拥有了列车控制权
- Citizens of Snowpiercer...
雪国列车的公民们…
We're back.
我们回来了
50 meters, 40 meters,
50米 40米
25 meters...
25米
- It can't be just over.
不可能就这样结束了
- Well, I think it's about time we get on the right side of history.
我觉得该是选择胜利一方的时候了
- Here you go.
给
Oz,
奥斯
I love you so much.
我非常爱你
- Long live the Resistance!
抵抗军万岁
- Ah, found it. - Ruth?
-找到了 -鲁丝
- Andre.
安德烈
- I never would have found you. You're in civvies.
你没穿制服 我都认不出你了
I remembered that Wilford had a secret tipple up here.
我记得威尔福德 把他的好酒藏在这里了
- Oh, could use some of that. - Wanna celebrate? - Yes.
-我正需要喝两口 没错 -我想着我们可以庆祝一下
- Oh, welcome home. It's good to have you back.
欢迎回来 你能回来真是太好了
- I knew you'd hold everyone together.
我就知道你能把大家团结在一起
Well done.
干得漂亮
- Let's do it.
我们来喝吧
- Take them out.
把他们放出来
- He's stable.
他情况稳定
Carly's stable. And Anne--
卡莉情况稳定…还有安娜…
- Javi.
哈维
Hey.
嘿
- Oh, man.
天啊
- This warm spot, the Horn of Africa, you really believe it can support life?
非洲之角这个暖点 你真的相信它能维持生命生长
- Yeah, our future is there, Ruth. I believe it with all my heart.
是的 鲁丝 我们的未来就在那里 我非常坚信这一点
- You know, the Horn of Africa, the approach is maybe the worst stretch of track on
通往非洲之角的轨道是整个铁路网内
the entire network.
最糟的一段
And there was a war there when the climate crashed.
而且气候崩溃时 那里发生过一场战争
- Yeah, yeah, I remember.
嗯 我记得
- The people are tired, Andre.
大家都累坏了 安德烈
It's been a long six months, and your first order
这六个月艰苦漫长 而你回来后的第一个命令
is gonna be to steer them right back into more hardship?
就是要让他们再经历更多艰辛
- Mm-mmm, there won't be an order. We'll put it to a vote.
我不会下达命令 我们会投票决定
- A vote? - Yeah.
-投票  -是的
We'll show them that democracy has won. We'll choose our path forward together.
我们要让大家看看 民主已经获胜 我们要一起选择前进的道路
- And you're prepared for the outcome of this vote?
你已经准备好面对投票结果了
- I am going to convince them that it is worth the risk.
我会让大家相信这值得冒险一试
Snowpiercer's running on duct tape and prayers.
雪国列车已经损毁不堪 不抛锚已是万幸
This is a real opportunity to get off.
这是一个真实的能下车的机会
- It's also a vote on you, Andre.
这也是对你的投票 安德烈
Much of the train doesn't support your leadership.
列车上的很多人并不支持你的领导
- This isn't just about me.
这件事不止关系到我
It's what Melanie would have wanted.
这也是梅兰妮会想要的
- All right.
那好
I'll, uh, inform the notary.
我去通知公证处
I know that everyone aboard will take their vote to heart,
我知道列车上的所有人 都会慎重地投出这一票
but are you prepared to accept it if they vote no?
但万一投票结果是“不去” 你有这思想准备吗
You better think long and hard about exactly what it is you're gonna tell them.
你最好仔细琢磨一下要怎么说服大家
- You're confined to Third and barred from the Nightcar.
只准你待在三等车厢 而且禁止进夜车
- Where's Joseph? - You picked the wrong side, Audrey.
-约瑟夫呢  -奥德丽 你站错队伍了
- Has there ever been a right side on this goddamn train?
这该死的列车上有过正确的队伍吗
It's all gonna go to shit. You'll see.
这一切都会崩塌的 等着瞧吧
- It went straight through my hand.
直接扎穿了我的手
- Something to remember us by.
这样你就能记住我们了
- Look at you.
看看你呀
A monster come for its creator.
怪物来找它的创造者
It's poetic, isn't it?
很有诗意吧
- Layton can't hold it together, you know.
雷顿没法把列车团结起来的
They'll reject him again.
他们会再次拒绝他的领导
I am the train.
我是这列车的灵魂
- A vote?
投票
- That's right.
没错
You'll get a vote today too.
你今天也会有投票的权利
Politics.
政治
You forget about them when you're the last person on Earth.
当你是世上最后一个人的时候 就会忘记政治的存在
Thank you.
谢谢你
- Don't thank me just yet.
先别忙着谢我
There's something I need to ask of you.
我有件事要你帮忙
- You brought me back to life, Andre.
安德烈 你救了我的命
What is it?
要我帮什么
- My fellow passengers...
各位乘客同伴们
Today, for the first time since our departure...
今天是这列列车启程以来第一次
you will have a say in our destination,
由你们来决定我们的目的地
and your choice will determine our future.
而且你们的选择将决定我们的未来
By now, you know that Melanie's sacrifice gave us a map.
你们已经知道 梅兰妮牺牲了自己 为我们绘制了一份地图
Proof that there are places on the Earth that are warming.
证明地球上有些地方正在变暖
Traveling fast and light, we tested each of them.
我们之前轻装出发 快速地测试了每一个暖点
Sulawesi, Gujarat, Managua,
苏拉威西岛、古吉拉特邦、马那瓜
the Atacama.
阿塔卡马
And each one of these let us down.
但它们都不合格
I know that you have suffered badly
我知道 当初我们分开列车的决定
because of our decision to break the train.
害你们历尽了艰苦
But there is one more location on which I ask you to stake your hope:
但还有一个地方 我觉得大家应该寄予希望
the Horn of Africa.
那就是非洲之角
The journey to return there will be fraught with risk
返回那里的行程会充满风险
and the hardships will continue,
艰辛还将继续
but we have someone here who can renew our faith.
但这里有一个人 能让我们重树信心
Someone we had given up on believing in.
一个我们以前觉得不可能存在的人
- What's he doing?
他这是在干什么
- But I'll let her tell you.
我会让她自己跟你们说
- He's bullshitting.
他在编瞎话
- My name is Asha.
我叫阿莎
I am a survivor.
我是一个幸存者
Layton found me out there, outside.
雷顿在外面找到了我
Along with trees,
在户外 生长了树木
green grass...
青草
and life.
和生命的地方
I come from New Eden.
我来自新伊甸园
- I'm not asking you to choose between me and Wilford.
我不是要你们 在我和威尔福德之间做出选择
I am asking you to choose between the train we know
而是请你们在我们熟悉的列车
and the dream we don't.
和我们不熟悉的梦想之间做出选择
Thank you all so much for your sacrifices.
非常感谢大家作出的牺牲
The story needed a hero, and we brought one back.
这个故事需要一个英雄 所以我们就带回了一个英雄
- Well, in the wake of that performance,
鉴于那番表演
the yeas have it.
投赞同票的人胜出
Almost two to one.
几乎是2比1的比例
- What's one more lie?
多说一个谎又怎样呢
- The difference is, this is the last one
区别在于 这是我们说的最后一个谎话
we will have to tell.
我很怀疑
- Well, I doubt that. I've come to think this train demands a lie.
我开始觉得这列列车需要谎言
- Yeah, like an imaginary genius in the engine.
没错 就像虚构的机车中的天才
- Or Melanie saving us with perfect science.
或是梅兰妮用完美的科学手段 来拯救我们
- Or a survivor to show us the way.
或是为我们指路的幸存者
- So...
所以…
we press on. - Agreed.
-我们继续前进 -同意
- What else are we gonna do?
我们还能怎样
- Josie?
乔西
- Well, we better be right.
我们最好是对的
- Fellow passengers, our great endeavor continues.
各位乘客同伴们 我们伟大的征程将继续
You have spoken, and by majority rule, we are heading for New Eden.
你们已表态 根据少数服从多数原则 我们将前往新伊甸园